Joshua Spears

Senior UI Engineer

joshuaspears29@gmail.com https://github.com/JaySpears joshspears.io 850.559.5020 Dallas | **TX**

Summary

I'm currently a devoted engineer with a heavy affection for JavaScript development. My skill set has been obtained from over 5 years of technical experience. Love a good challenge when it comes to problem solving anything software related. Remaining curious and focused in languages, frameworks, and technologies are important to me. Development is more than a job to me. It's a **passion**.

• • •

Experience

Ansira (Formerly Sq1) | *Senior UI Engineer*

August 2017 - Present

- Lead Engineer for a large Angular and Express application for Shell Oil. This authorized application was built for client representives to login into and create offers for specifc customers, which in return would create landing pages for them.
- Worked with a vendor to build an application for Shell Global (Indonesia). My role in this project was to build the client (Angular) and server (Express) application to post data to the vendors CRM. This project was built to help distributors closely manage their product sells.
- Maintained a medium size Express application for Jiffy Lube. This MVC application uses CRUD for product offers. Also provides dynamic email generation (Submitted, Live, Expired, etc.) for when offers are updated in the super admin platform. These offers would be served to the front end for dynamic landing pages.
- Worked with Coke to build a static responsive splash page for their internal users. This splash page helped users understand the functionality of Coke's internal portal.
- Provided oversight and guidance for a third-party website refresh (LowT).
- Helped the media time configure tracking with the help of Adobe DTM.
- Mentored junior developers and helped them problem solve. We would do some pair programming at times, depending on the project scope/length.
- Screen and interviewed potential candidates that could fit the culture.

Ansira (Formerly Sq1) | *Interactive Developer*

January 2016 - August 2017

- Maintained a digital campaigns platform for Shell Oil. Project was built using Angular with the help of the node framework, Sails.
- Designed modular component based SASS architecture for limitless Shell Oil clients.
- Used Google Maps API to build dynamic interactive and static maps for Shell Oil.
- Utilized an AWS S3 bucket instance to handle Shell Oil customer assets.
- Followed the John Papa style guide when building Angular applications.
- Discussed architecture of websites with the creative department to produce web responsive PSD's.
- Tested with Quality Assurance to solve issue resolution over multiple browsers, and mobile devices.
- Configured A/B testing with VWO.

Sq1 | *Jr. Developer (Front End)*

April 2015 - December 2015

- Built a custom Wordpress theme for Greatbatch Medical. (integer.net)
- Responsible for time-sensitive deliveries for client projects as well as weekly maintenance for multiple projects.
- Implemented modern technologies to existing projects, this helped improve development process.
- Worked with responsive PSD's via Layer Comps provided by creative departments.
- Created responsive architecture utilizing CSS grids from Zurb Foundation and Bootstrap.
- Collaborated with Project Management to understand project process, and deadlines.

Sq1 | Web Development Intern

September 2014 - April 2015

- Integrated with a vendor team to build a completely custom website on a large third-party E-commerce platform. (petmate.com)
- Assisted in developing responsive websites, and mobile applications via PSDs.
- Studied and wrote HMTL, CSS, and JavaScript up to 30 hours a week.
- Learned and practiced a version control management system (Git).
- Shadowed senior developers as they built architectural client web applications.

• • •

Skills

Front End Development

• JavaScript, SASS, CSS, HTML, HBS.

Back End Development

Node.js, Postgres, mySql.

Frameworks, Libraries.

- Front End: React.js, Redux, Angular.js, jQuery, Zurb Foundation, Boostrap.
- Back End: Express, Sails.

Additional Knowledge

• Babel, Bower, ES7, Git, Gulp, JSON, npm, Vagrant, Webpack. (These are just a **few** additional knowledge tools I use.)

• • •

Education

Tallahassee Community College

August 2012 - December 2014

Continued Education

Self Taught Development

2011 - Present